runningahead.com 2014-01-27

# RunningAHEAD

Last Updated May 9, 2011

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the RunningAHEAD, LLC Terms of Service and serves to notify you of the following:

  * [Where and when is information collected (including through the use of cookies and action tags)?]()
  * [Is information that i submit to the public areas of the Service private?]()
  * [Does RunningAHEAD collect information from children under 13 years of age? ]()
  * [When does RunningAHEAD disclose information to third parties? ]()
  * [Does this privacy policy apply when I link to other web sites? ]()
  * [What choices do I have regarding the collection, disclosure and distribution of personally identifiable information? ]()
  * [Can I update or correct my personally identifiable information? ]()
  * [How will I know if there are any changes to this privacy policy? ]()

## WHAT INFORMATION ABOUT ME IS COLLECTED?

Depending on your use of the websites, applications (including mobile apps) and/or other services we, RunningAHEAD, LLC ("RunningAHEAD" "we" or "us" or "our") may make available from time to time (collectively, and together with associated and successor websites, applications and services, the "Service"), we may collect two types of information: personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information.

## Personally Identifiable Information 

Personally identifiable information is information that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you. Such information may include your name, address, email address, telephone number, and billing and credit card information. 

## Non-Personally Identifiable Information

Non-personally identifiable information is information that any single of item of which, by itself, cannot be used to identify or contact you, such as demographic information (like age, profession, gender, current location, zip code, birth date, or year of birth). Non-personally identifiable information may also include user IP addresses, browser types, domain names, purchasing or usage history and trends, and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of the Service. 

## WHERE AND WHEN IS INFORMATION COLLECTED (INCLUDING THROUGH THE USE OF COOKIES AND ACTION TAGS)?

We will collect personally identifiable information from you only if you voluntarily submit the information to us. We may also receive personally identifiable information about you from third parties providing credit and debit card authorization and fraud screening services as part of your use of the Service. 

## Registering to Use the Service and in the Course of Using the Service.

You may be required to establish an account in order to take advantage of certain features of the Service. If so, if you wish to establish an account you will be required to provide us with information (including personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information) such as name, postal address, email address, birth date and credit card and billing information. We may also receive personally identifiable information about you from third parties providing credit and debit card authorization and fraud screening services as part of the registration process. In addition, we may obtain your personally identifiable information from you if you identify yourself to us by sending us an email with questions or comments.

## Cookies and Action Tags.

We collect non-personally identifiable information passively using "cookies" and "action tags."

"Cookies" are small text files that are placed on your computer or mobile device in order to identify your Web browser and the activities of your computer on the Service and other websites. Cookies are used to personalize your experience on the Service (such as dynamically generating content on webpages specifically designed for you), to assist you in using the Service (such as saving time by not having to reenter your name each time you use the Service), and to allow us to statistically monitor how you are using the Service to help us improve our offerings. We also may use cookies to target certain advertisements to your browser which may be of interest to you or to determine the popularity of certain content.

In addition to cookies that we place on your computer or mobile device, cookies may also be placed on your computer or mobile device by third parties that we use to display or serve advertisements or to collect non-personally identifiable information in order to provide advertising-related services. In the course of serving advertisements, our third-party advertisers may place or recognize unique cookies on your browser.

You do not have to accept cookies to use the Service. Although most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, you may reset your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to reject cookies generally. Most browsers offer instructions on how to do so in the "Help" section of the toolbar. While you are not required to accept our cookies to access the Service, if you reject cookies, certain products, offerings, features, or resources of the Service may not work properly and you may experience some loss of convenience.

"Action tags," also known as web beacons or gif tags, are a web technology used to help track website usage information, such as how many times a specific page has been viewed. Action tags are invisible to you, and any portion of the Service, including advertisements, or email sent on our behalf, may contain action tags.

By using cookies and action tags together, we are able to gain valuable information to improve the Service and measure the effectiveness of our advertising and marketing campaigns. 

Finally, you should be aware that advertisers and other third parties may also use their own cookies or action tags when you click on their advertisement or link to their websites or services on or from the Service. This Privacy Policy does not govern the use by such third-party websites or services or providers of third-party advertising.

## Log Files.

We also collect non-personally identifiable information through our Internet log files, which record data such as user IP addresses, browser types, domain names, and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of the Service. This information may be used to analyze trends, to administer the Service, to monitor the use of the Service, and to gather general demographic information. We may link this information to personally identifiable information for these and other purposes such as personalizing your experience on the Service and evaluating the Service in general.

## Analytics Services.

We may utilize third party service providers and services to analyze and provide statistics about the use of the Service, such as Google Analytics. may involve us "page tags" or other tracking code to track visitor data and send it the third parties' data collection servers for processing on our behalf. 

## IS INFORMATION THAT I SUBMIT TO THE PUBLIC AREAS OF THE SERVICE PRIVATE?

Any information (including training logs, routes, and photographs) that you share in the public areas of the Service is available to all members and users, and any information that you share with a group within the Service is available to all members and users who are members of the group. Additionally, any information that you permit us to make available to Facebook is available to Facebook members and users. Any information that you make publicly available or otherwise disclose to others is not protected or treated as confidential, can be used in any manner, and is not subject to this Privacy Policy. If you wish to keep any information private or proprietary, do not submit it to the public or group areas of the Service. WE HAVE NO RESPONSIBILITY OR LIABILITY IF YOUR INFORMATION OR IDENTIFY IS MISUSED OR STOLEN, OR IF YOU SUFFER HARM AS A RESULT OF YOUR VOLUNTARY DISCLOSURES. 

## DOES RUNNINGAHEAD COLLECT INFORMATION FROM CHILDREN UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE?

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. The Service is not designed for or directed to children under the age of 13. We do not collect personally identifiable information from any person we actually know is under the age of 13.

## WHAT DOES RUNNINGAHEAD DO WITH THE INFORMATION IT COLLECTS?

In general, we use the information collected to provide the Service to you and process your transactions, to help us understand who uses the Service, for internal operations such as operating and improving the Service, to contact you for customer service and billing purposes, to facilitate the delivery of advertising, and so that we and third parties can contact you about products and services that may be of interest to you.

We may use your information to send you a welcoming email that may confirm your user name and password. If you "opt-in," we and third parties may send you electronic newsletters, contact you about the Service, products, services, information and news that may be of interest to you, and provide you with targeted feedback. If you no longer desire to receive these communications, we will provide you with the option to change your preferences. In addition, if you identify yourself to us by sending us an email with questions or comments, we may use your information (including personally identifiable information) to respond to your questions or comments, and we may file your questions or comments for future reference. We may also use the information collected to send you important service announcements and updates regarding the Service or, if applicable, about your billing account status. You will not be able to unsubscribe from these service announcements and updates as they contain important information relevant to your use of the Service.

We may also use the information gathered to perform statistical analysis of user behavior or to evaluate and improve the Service. We may link some of this information to personally identifiable information for internal purposes or to improve your experience with the Service.

## WHEN DOES RUNNINGAHEAD DISCLOSE INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES?

Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically authorized by you, we will not disclose any information we gather from you through the Service.

## Laws and Legal Rights.

We may disclose your information (including personally identifiable information) if we believe in good faith that we are required to do so in order to comply with an applicable statute, regulation, rule or law, a subpoena, a search warrant, a court or regulatory order, or other valid legal process. We may disclose personally identifiable information in special circumstances when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating the Terms of Service for our Service, to detect fraud, for assistance with delinquent accounts, or to protect the safety and/or security of our users, the Service or the general public.

## Third Parties Generally.

We may provide to third parties non-personally identifiable information, including where such information is combined with similar information of other users of the Service. For example, we might inform third parties regarding the number of unique users who use the Service, the demographic breakdown of our users of the Service, or the products and/or services purchased using the Service and the vendors of such products and services. We may also provide to third parties personally identifiable information. For example, we might share our users' responses to questionnaires and e-mail addresses with third parties in order for third parties to contact users about products and services that may be of interest. The third parties to which we may provide personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information may include potential or actual advertisers, providers of advertising products or services (including vendors and website tracking services), merchants, affiliates and other actual or potential commercial partners, sponsors, licensees, researchers and other similar parties.

## Outside Contractors.

We may employ independent contractors, vendors and suppliers (collectively, "Outside Contractors") to provide specific services and products related to the Service, such as hosting and maintaining the Service, providing credit card processing and fraud screening, and developing applications for the Service and e-mail services. In the course of providing products or services to us, these Outside Contractors may sometimes have limited access to information collected on the Service, including your personally identifiable information. We require that these contractors (1) protect the privacy of your personally identifiable information consistent with this Privacy Policy, and (2) not use or disclose your personally identifiable information for any purpose other than providing us with the products or services for which we contracted.

## Third Party Sellers.

In addition, through the Service, you may be given the opportunity to purchase (or to obtain more information regarding) certain content, products or services that are sold by parties other than us (collectively, "Merchants"). As noted above, in some circumstances, we may share personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information with third parties, including Merchants, so that they can contact you about products and services that may be of interest. Merchants may request that you submit certain information to them in order to purchase their products or services or to obtain additional information from them. By submitting the requested information, you affirmatively consent to have that information shared with the Merchant. This information is used by the Merchant and may be subject to a different privacy policy. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of Merchants. We encourage you to be aware when the Service links to Merchants' websites and to read the privacy policies or statements of each and every Merchant website. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected through the Service. 

## Sale of Business.

We reserve the right to transfer information to a third party in the event of a sale, merger or other transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of RunningAHEAD, or that portion of RunningAHEAD to which the Service relates, provided that the third party agrees to adhere to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

## Affiliates.

We may disclose information (including personally identifiable information) about you to our Corporate Affiliates. For purposes of this Privacy Policy, "Corporate Affiliate" means any person or entity which directly or indirectly controls, is controlled by or is under common control with RunningAHEAD, whether by ownership or otherwise. Any information relating to you that we provide to our Corporate Affiliates will be treated by those Corporate Affiliates in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

## DOES THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLY WHEN I LINK TO OTHER WEB SERVICES?

Our Service may contain links to other websites and services, integrate widgets, and utilize payment services not owned or operated by RunningAHEAD (for example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement, you will likely be taken off the Service, and if you make a payment you may be directed to our payment service provider's service). However, please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such websites, services and widgets. We encourage you to be aware when the Service links to or otherwise utilizes other websites, services and widgets and to read the privacy policies or statements of each and every such website, service and widget. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected through the Service.

## IS THE INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH THE SERVICE SECURE?

We want your information (including personally identifiable information) to remain secure. We strive to provide transmission of your information from your computer to our servers through techniques that are consistent with industry standards. 

Notwithstanding the above, you should be aware that there is always some risk involved in transmitting information over the Internet. There is also some risk that others could find a way to thwart our security systems. As a result, while we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security or privacy of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.

## COULD MY INFORMATION BE TRANSFERRED TO OTHER COUNTRIES?

Personally-identifiable information collected on the Service may be transferred from time to time to our offices or personnel, or to third parties, located throughout the world, and the Service may be viewed and hosted anywhere in the world, including countries (such as the United States) that may not have laws of general applicability regulating the use and transfer of such data. By using the Service and submitting such information on it, you voluntarily consent to the trans-border transfer and hosting of such information. If you are a user accessing the Service from a jurisdiction with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure that differ from those of the United States, please be advised that all aspects of the Service are governed by the internal laws of the United States and the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, regardless of your location.

## WHAT CHOICES DO I HAVE REGARDING THE COLLECTION, DISCLOSURE AND DISTRIBUTION OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION?

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, we will only use personally identifiable information for the purposes described above or as otherwise disclosed at the time we request such information from you. You must "opt-in" and give us permission to use your personally identifiable information for any other purpose. You may also change your preference and "opt-out" of receiving certain marketing communications by changing that option in the My Profile feature of the Service, following the directions provided in association with the communication, or by contacting privacy@runningahead.com.

## CAN I UPDATE OR CORRECT MY PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION?

You have the right to request the restriction of certain uses and disclosures of personally identifiable information as follows. You can contact us in order to (1) update or correct your personally identifiable information, (2) change your preferences with respect to communications and other information you receive from us, or (3) delete the personally identifiable information maintained about you on our systems (subject to the following paragraph), by accessing My Profile or contacting privacy@runningahead.com. Such updates, corrections, changes and deletions will not have an effect on other information that we maintain, or information that we have provided to third-parties in accordance with this Privacy Policy prior to such update, correction, change or deletion. To protect your privacy and security, we may take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identify before granting you profile access or making corrections. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times.

You should be aware that it is not technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided to us from our system. The need to back-up our systems to protect information from inadvertent loss means that a copy of your personally identifiable information may exist in a non-erasable form that will be difficult or impossible for us to locate. We promise that promptly after receiving your request, all personally identifiable information stored in databases we actively use and other readily searchable media will be updated, corrected, changed or deleted, as appropriate, as soon as and to the extent reasonably practicable.

## HOW WILL I KNOW IF THERE ARE ANY CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY?

You should be aware that we may revise this Privacy Policy at any time. However, we will not make changes that result in significant additional uses or disclosures of your personally identifiable information without allowing you to "Opt In" to such changes. We may also make non-significant changes to this Privacy Policy that generally will not significantly affect our use of your personally identifiable information. We encourage you to check this page periodically for any changes. Your continued use of the Service following the posting of non-significant changes to this Privacy Policy will mean you accept those changes.

## WHOM DO I CONTACT IF I HAVE ANY PRIVACY QUESTIONS?

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or feel that we are not abiding by the terms of this Privacy Policy, please contact our Privacy Agent by sending an email to privacy@runningahead.com

BY USING THE SERVICE, YOU SIGNIFY YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU SHOULD NOT USE THE SERVICE.
